<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>rust on Bitcoin Dev Kit</title>
    <link>https://bitcoindevkit.org/blog/tags/rust/</link>
    <description>Recent content in rust on Bitcoin Dev Kit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bitcoindevkit.org/blog/tags/rust/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Release v0.5.0</title>
      <link>https://bitcoindevkit.org/blog/2021/03/release-v0.5.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bitcoindevkit.org/blog/2021/03/release-v0.5.0/</guid>
      <description>A new release of BDK is out: v0.5.0 is our first release licensed under Apache 2.0 and MIT, brings new features, bugfixes and some internal refactoring.
You can find the full v0.5.0 changelog on GitHub.
What&amp;rsquo;s new in v0.5.0 Below are some highlights of the new release:
Dual Licensing From now on BDK will be released under both Apache 2.0 and MIT, at your discretion. This change aligns our project with many other Rust crates and reiterates our commitment to a permissive licensing model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release v0.4.0</title>
      <link>https://bitcoindevkit.org/blog/2021/02/release-v0.4.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bitcoindevkit.org/blog/2021/02/release-v0.4.0/</guid>
      <description>A new release of BDK is out: the v0.4.0 release brings updated dependencies, more sanity checks and an overhauled API to build transactions.
You can find the full v0.4.0 changelog on GitHub.
What&amp;rsquo;s new in v0.4.0 Below are some highlights of the new improved APIs coming with this release:
A new API to build transaction The star of this release is the new API designed and implemented by @llfourn that brings much more flexibility to the way we create transactions: originally the process of making a transaction involved the creation of a TxBuilder which was used to configure how the wallet should build the transaction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release v0.3.0</title>
      <link>https://bitcoindevkit.org/blog/2021/01/release-v0.3.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bitcoindevkit.org/blog/2021/01/release-v0.3.0/</guid>
      <description>A new release of BDK is out: the v0.3.0 is a relatively small update compared to v0.2.0, but it still brings some nice APIs improvements and general bugfixes.
You can find the full v0.3.0 changelog on GitHub.
What&amp;rsquo;s new in v0.3.0 Below are some highlights of the new improved APIs coming with this release:
Less verbosity when using Wallet::new_offline() Now you don&amp;rsquo;t have to explicitly provide the OfflineWallet&amp;lt;_&amp;gt; type anymore, saving you one import and making it much less verbose to use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release v0.2.0</title>
      <link>https://bitcoindevkit.org/blog/2020/12/release-v0.2.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bitcoindevkit.org/blog/2020/12/release-v0.2.0/</guid>
      <description>A new release of BDK is finally out! The v0.2.0 release contains many exciting new features, bug fixes and overall improvements. This release also marks the beginning of our new regular release schedule, which will see us pushing out a new release every four weeks. We think this is a good compromise to ensure that developers using BDK have access to all the new features and fixes as soon as possible, at least while the library is still evolving very fast as it is right now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World!</title>
      <link>https://bitcoindevkit.org/blog/2020/12/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bitcoindevkit.org/blog/2020/12/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This article should serve as a &amp;ldquo;getting started&amp;rdquo; guide for developers who are considering integrating BDK in their projects: it tries to introduce the reader to the basic concepts behind the library and some of its modules and components that can be used to build a very simple functioning Bitcoin wallet. All the information written in this article are valid for the current master git branch, and should remain valid for the upcoming v0.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
