<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Riccardo Casatta on Bitcoin Dev Kit</title>
    <link>https://bitcoindevkit.org/blog/author/riccardo-casatta/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Riccardo Casatta on Bitcoin Dev Kit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bitcoindevkit.org/blog/author/riccardo-casatta/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fee estimation for light-clients (Part 1)</title>
      <link>https://bitcoindevkit.org/blog/2021/01/fee-estimation-for-light-clients-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bitcoindevkit.org/blog/2021/01/fee-estimation-for-light-clients-part-1/</guid>
      <description>This post is part 1 of 3 of a series. (Part 2, Part 3)
 Introduction: what is fee estimation? The problem  The challenges and the solution The question The data logger    Introduction: what is fee estimation? Fee estimation is the process of selecting the fee rate1 for a bitcoin transaction being created, according to two main factors:
 The current congestion of the Bitcoin network. The urgency, or lack thereof, for the transaction confirmation, i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fee estimation for light-clients (Part 2)</title>
      <link>https://bitcoindevkit.org/blog/2021/01/fee-estimation-for-light-clients-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bitcoindevkit.org/blog/2021/01/fee-estimation-for-light-clients-part-2/</guid>
      <description>This post is part 2 of 3 of a series. (Part 1, Part 3)
 The dataset  The mempool The outliers Recap    The dataset The dataset is publicly available (~500MB gzip compressed, ~2GB as plain CSV).
The output of the model is the fee rate, expressed in [satoshi/vbytes].
What about the inputs? Generally speaking, we have two main requirements for what can be included as input for our model:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fee estimation for light-clients (Part 3)</title>
      <link>https://bitcoindevkit.org/blog/2021/01/fee-estimation-for-light-clients-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bitcoindevkit.org/blog/2021/01/fee-estimation-for-light-clients-part-3/</guid>
      <description>This post is part 3 of 3 of a series. (Part 1, Part 2)
 The model  Splitting Preprocessing Build Finally, training   The prediction phase Conclusion and future development Acknowledgements  The model The code building and training the model with tensorflow is available in google colab notebook (jupyter notebook); you can also download the file as plain python and run it locally. At least 1 hour is needed to train the full model, but it heavily depends on the hardware available.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
