<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Bitcoin Dev Kit</title>
    <link>https://bitcoindevkit.org/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Bitcoin Dev Kit</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://bitcoindevkit.org/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Fee estimation for light-clients (Part 1)</title>
      <link>https://bitcoindevkit.org/blog/2021/01/fee-estimation-for-light-clients-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bitcoindevkit.org/blog/2021/01/fee-estimation-for-light-clients-part-1/</guid>
      <description>This post is part 1 of 3 of a series. (Part 2, Part 3)
 Introduction: what is fee estimation? The problem  The challenges and the solution The question The data logger    Introduction: what is fee estimation? Fee estimation is the process of selecting the fee rate1 for a bitcoin transaction being created, according to two main factors:
 The current congestion of the Bitcoin network. The urgency, or lack thereof, for the transaction confirmation, i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fee estimation for light-clients (Part 2)</title>
      <link>https://bitcoindevkit.org/blog/2021/01/fee-estimation-for-light-clients-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bitcoindevkit.org/blog/2021/01/fee-estimation-for-light-clients-part-2/</guid>
      <description>This post is part 2 of 3 of a series. (Part 1, Part 3)
 The dataset  The mempool The outliers Recap    The dataset The dataset is publicly available (~500MB gzip compressed, ~2GB as plain CSV).
The output of the model is the fee rate, expressed in [satoshi/vbytes].
What about the inputs? Generally speaking, we have two main requirements for what can be included as input for our model:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fee estimation for light-clients (Part 3)</title>
      <link>https://bitcoindevkit.org/blog/2021/01/fee-estimation-for-light-clients-part-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bitcoindevkit.org/blog/2021/01/fee-estimation-for-light-clients-part-3/</guid>
      <description>This post is part 2 of 3 of a series. (Part 1, Part 2)
 The model  Splitting Preprocessing Build Finally, training   The prediction phase Conclusion and future development Acknowledgements  The model The code building and training the model with tensorflow is available in google colab notebook (jupyter notebook); you can also download the file as plain python and run it locally. At least 1 hour is needed to train the full model, but it heavily depends on the hardware available.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release v0.3.0</title>
      <link>https://bitcoindevkit.org/blog/2021/01/release-v0.3.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bitcoindevkit.org/blog/2021/01/release-v0.3.0/</guid>
      <description>A new release of BDK is out: the v0.3.0 is a relatively small update compared to v0.2.0, but it still brings some nice APIs improvements and general bugfixes.
You can find the full v0.3.0 changelog on GitHub.
What&amp;rsquo;s new in v0.3.0 Below are some highlights of the new improved APIs coming with this release:
Less verbosity when using Wallet::new_offline() Now you don&amp;rsquo;t have to explicitly provide the OfflineWallet&amp;lt;_&amp;gt; type anymore, saving you one import and making it much less verbose to use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Release v0.2.0</title>
      <link>https://bitcoindevkit.org/blog/2020/12/release-v0.2.0/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bitcoindevkit.org/blog/2020/12/release-v0.2.0/</guid>
      <description>A new release of BDK is finally out! The v0.2.0 release contains many exciting new features, bug fixes and overall improvements. This release also marks the beginning of our new regular release schedule, which will see us pushing out a new release every four weeks. We think this is a good compromise to ensure that developers using BDK have access to all the new features and fixes as soon as possible, at least while the library is still evolving very fast as it is right now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hello World!</title>
      <link>https://bitcoindevkit.org/blog/2020/12/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bitcoindevkit.org/blog/2020/12/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This article should serve as a &amp;ldquo;getting started&amp;rdquo; guide for developers who are considering integrating BDK in their projects: it tries to introduce the reader to the basic concepts behind the library and some of its modules and components that can be used to build a very simple functioning Bitcoin wallet. All the information written in this article are valid for the current master git branch, and should remain valid for the upcoming v0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Descriptors in the wild</title>
      <link>https://bitcoindevkit.org/blog/2020/11/descriptors-in-the-wild/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://bitcoindevkit.org/blog/2020/11/descriptors-in-the-wild/</guid>
      <description>I have tried to setup a 2 of 2 multi signature infrastructure with two different wallets, which know nothing about each other, but are compliant with two very important protocols: Output Descriptors and Partially Signed Bitcoin Transactions described in BIP 174.
Before these two protocols came into existence, making a multi signature setup and spending from it was possible only if the involved parties were using the same wallet (eg. Electrum Desktop Wallet).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
